Turn to your neighbour and greet them, "Emmanuel!" (God With Us - Matthew 1:23).
Give your neighbour a handshake and say, "Emmanuel!" (God With Us - Matthew 1:23).
Give your other neighbour a handshake and say, "Emmanuel!" (God With Us - Matthew 1:23).
Give the neighbour behind you a handshake and say, "Emmanuel!" (God With Us - Matthew 1:23).
Give the neighbour in front of you a handshake and say, "Emmanuel!" (God With Us - Matthew 1:23).
Greet the viewers all over the world on Emmanuel TV, "Emmanuel!" (God With Us - Matthew 1:23).
Yes, indeed, God is with us.
Whilst we are still standing, let's quickly pray together.
Oh Holy Spirit, we ask You right now that You would open the door of our hearts.
Help us not just to be mere hearers of Your Word but to be doers of Your Word
and let Your Word penetrate deep into our hearts, in Jesus' name.
And the people of God said...
[Amen!]
Amen. Right now, you may have your seats in the presence of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Good Morning, Church!
My name is Brother Chris from the UK
and I have the wonderful, incredible privilege today
of sharing with you the life-changing message of Jesus Christ.
I want to acknowledge God for what He has done in my life through Prophet T.B. Joshua
and the grace that God has given me to be here in your midst this morning.
Now today, I want to talk about something that I believe affects everyone,
but most especially this generation we are living in today
because you would agree with me that we are living in a very impatient generation.
Tell your neighbour, "We are living in an impatient generation".
Do you know what I mean by impatience?
You see people rushing up and down, hurrying up and down,
everything we want it now, this instant.
This is the generation we are living in today.
I just want to tell you a very quick story.
This is a true story - I guarantee you.
A couple of months ago, I was with one of my colleagues in our room.
He was in a rush; he was in a haste.
He wanted to go to the studio for an assignment.
And he quickly went to the toilet first.
When he came out of the toilet, the bathroom, his face looked a little bit distressed
and he said, "Chris, I think I need prayer".
"Prayer, what? You just went to the toilet! What has happened?"
He said, "Do you know what just happened?
I was in such a rush to leave the toilet that I flushed the toilet before I even used it".
I hope you understand what I mean.
He was in such a rush to leave the toilet
that before he sat down to use it, he flushed first
so he would not have to flush after he had finished using it.
Now, why am I saying this little story?
Because our generation today is an impatient generation.
We are in a generation of fast food, microwaves, instant connectivity through the internet.
We want things now, we want things quick, we want things sudden.
We want to take a shortcut, the quickest route.
That is the generation we are living in today.
And the truth, brethren, is that impatience is costly.
If you examine yourself, I think you would agree with me that
many of your greatest mistakes in life have happened as a result of impatience.
When we are impatient, we tend to disregard the fact that there is a time for everything.
That is how God has decreed and declared it;
God has set the right time for everything in this world.
Just look at the day, the sun comes out; when it is night, the moon appears -
they don't swap or exchange positions.
Have you ever heard the sun say to the moon,
"Please, do you mind covering my shift for a couple of hours? I have got a bit of a backpain".
Have you ever heard the moon calling out to the sun and saying,
"Do you mind, next week I'm going out with my wife for dinner.
Do you mind covering for that night for the sun to just come out?"
No! They don't swap, they don't exchange positions - they are fixed.
God has set an appointed time and season for everything that has to do with us.
There is a time to grow,
a time to face challenges, persecution and troubles.
There is a time to overcome and there is a time to show the proceeds of victory.
There is a time for everything.
Tell your neighbour, "There is a time for everything".
Tell your other neighbour, "There is a time for everything".
In our impatient generation today, so often we don't wait for God's appointed time
because our hearts are so busy, occupied with worldly considerations -
we are comparing ourselves with others.
"Everyone at my age range is getting married. I need to get married."
"Everyone is planning for this particular business at this time.
I need to join them as well."
Because of that, we are quick to make decisions out of impatience
and your greatest mistakes will happen because of impatience.
Just check your life; check yourself.
Whenever you are in a hurry, you easily make a mistake
and oftentimes, that mistake can be costly - costly mistakes that may pull you back or down.
So I want to tell you today:
First and foremost, God's response is not for those in a hurry.
Tell your neighbour, "God's response is not for those in a hurry".
This means, people of God, that we should be patient and let God answer us on His schedule, not ours
because at God's time, everything is beautiful.
Now this brings us to the title of today's message: 'No Reason To Rush'
Tell your neighbour, "Neighbour" - just give your neighbour a bit of a warning finger!
Say, "Neighbour, take it easy! There is no reason to rush!"
Now you can give your neighbour a pad and say,
"Neighbour, calm down. There is no reason to rush!"
Now talk to yourself, say your name, "My name, be still. There is no reason to rush!
Calm down; take it easy".
Because we are in such a rush today.
So we are going to deal with that impatience.
Turn with me in your Bible to the Book of Hebrews 6:11-12
which is our proof text for today's message.
Hebrews 6:11-12.
"We want each of you to show this same diligence to the very end..."
Tell your neighbour, "To the very end".
If what you enjoy does not last to the end, it is not of God.
To the end.
Blessed is he who endures to the end.
You may be great but without preparation and time that greatness will not last to the end.
You can have some levels of success but without preparation and time
you will face challenges that will topple that success.
You may be blessed but without preparation and time
that blessing will be fading away until it's gone at the time you need it most.
To the end - now let's continue.
It says, "We want each of you to show this same diligence to the very end,
so that what you hope for may be fully realised.
We do not want you to become lazy, but to imitate those who through faith and patience
inherit what has been promised".
What is the Scripture talking about here?
Faith coupled with patience inherits the promises of God.
As Christians, our tools are patience, perseverance and endurance.
These are our tools, our instruments.
Now just imagine, you are in your house, and you have a fault with your shower.
Maybe the shower has stopped working or maybe the toilet has stopped working
because people keep flushing before instead of afterwards
and you have to call a plumber.
You call a plumber to your house to come and fix this problem.
And the plumber comes in, and you show him the problem,
"Please, Mr Plumber, help me out here. The water is gone.
I can't shower; I can't use the toilet".
The plumber says, "I can fix the problem but do you have any tools?"
"What? You're the plumber. You are supposed to bring the tools!
What do you mean you come to my house to fix this problem and you don't have tools?
How can you solve this problem without your tools?
Without your spanner, your this, that -
all of the tools necessary to open up the shower and correct the problem?
You don't have your tools and you come to fix the problem?"
I think you would question the genuineness of that plumber.
You may likely say, "The plumber is a quack".
You may likely call the company and complain,
"You sent a plumber to my house without any tools!"
As a Christian, how can your genuineness be confirmed if we don't see your tools -
your patience, perseverance and endurance?
Hebrews 12:1-2 says that we should run the race with perseverance.
Perseverance is an essential instrument for our faith.
Patience, perseverance, forbearance, endurance are the tools of genuine Christians.
But brethren, so many times today, when we face a test of faith,
we begin to look for alternatives, shortcuts because we lack those tools.
We are too impatient to wait for God's time.
The Bible says that faith strengthens the believer to persevere
even when the promise of God seems to delay in its fulfilment.
Many times, we are struggling, striving against a certain challenge, obstacle, problem
and we don't seem to be able to overcome.
It is so easy for us to get frustrated but we don't know that God is testing our faith.
Let me try - quick example.
We like examples in these messages.
Can I get three chairs, please.
Thank you very much.
Just a quick example to demonstrate the importance of patience, perseverance and endurance.
Alright. Are you with me, people of God?
I want to hear you. Are you with me, people of God?
So this is my journey to the throne as a Christian.
My journey to where God has destined me to meet my destiny.
I want to show you my destiny in this particular example.
This is my destiny.
See the wonderful fruits that God has waiting for me.
But in the journey to my destiny, I have some obstacles, challenges, troubles, temptations.
Now, in the course of my journey as a Christian, I meet this obstacle
and I try with my natural strength, I try everything to move the obstacle,
I try with my intelligence, wisdom, connections - no way!
The obstacle refuses to budge.
It is a tiring exercise.
I want to tell you the identifying qualities of Christians.
Christians have no alternatives.
Shortcuts are not part of our vocabulary.
Alternatives have no definition in our dictionary.
We only have one way - Jesus.
Jesus is not a way; Jesus is not one of the ways.
Jesus is The Way, The Truth, The Life.
There is only one way to our destiny - Jesus!
There is no other way.
So if I meet this obstacle and I'm trying to move it -
I have fasted, I have prayed, I tried everything
and the obstacle refuses to budge - what do I do as a Christian?
I wait patiently for the Lord.
To a man of faith, delay is not denial.
Don't misinterpret God's silence as rejection.
Even when He seems to be quiet, God is still saying something.
Perhaps in this obstacle, God is telling you, He is speaking to you,
saying, "My son, be patient. I'm preparing you for the challenges ahead".
"My daughter, be patient. There is no reason to rush.
I'm strengthening your desire for Me."
Because there is a time and a season for everything.
But our generation today - impatience, in a hurry, haste, rush -
we meet this obstacle, we are trying to move it - no way.
We begin to look around, "Maybe, there is another way".
The moment you have that thought, "There is another way, a shortcut, an alternative",
don't worry; satan is there to provide you one.
"Pst, Chris, come over here."
"What? Where?"
"This way, this way! Come! This way!"
"What is going on?"
"Chris, go upstairs. There is a quick way. God doesn't want you to know that way
but it will take you straight to the destiny, straight to the throne,
a shortcut, not all these obstacles. Let's go.
Come on, let me show you the shortcut.
I will show you the shortcut right now."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Satan says, "Look it is just this way. Just round the corner.
You will get there very fast".
Because we are so young, we believe we can do it on our own, without reverence to God.
We trust our wisdom, intelligence, connections, science, organisations, works.
We say, "Ok, let's go".
Now, the first thing that happens when you take an alternative - let me tell you.
When you leave God's ways, you are on your own.
What does this mean?
No guard, no guide.
No protection, no direction.
Satan can easily strike.
Satan can easily hit you.
He can hit you with temptation, destruction, distraction.
But before you know, you think you are on your way to your destiny -
you just take time, maybe there is a friend there, sit down and have a chat,
start a business conversation, business deal going on -
you are delaying; instead of you to be moving to your destiny, you are moving away;
instead of you to be closer to God, you are drawing away.
Satan may suddenly send a beautiful lady your way - temptation comes,
temptation strikes.
All of the time, the direction you took that you thought would take you on a shortcut
is ending up taking you away from your destiny, away from the ways of God.
We are deceived.
In this process, many of us touch what we are not supposed to touch,
we begin to taste what we are not supposed to taste,
we begin to see what we are not supposed to see.
When you get to a point here and say, "How do I go on?,
they say, "Look this man over here will help you.
He has connections, money, this, that, everything.
But he needs you to do this.
You must do this first".
Compromise your faith, compromise your Christianity.
"You must do this, you must do that. Join this association, join this society."
In the process of trying to beat God's appointed time,
many of us find ourselves entangled with conditions we are unable to meet,
thus jeopardising our career and the promise of God in our lives.
But some of us can even steal, kill, destroy,
thinking that we are going to get to our destiny,
not knowing that we are being led on a wild goose chase.
You say, "I must be getting there yet; I must be nearly there!
What is happening? I must almost be there!"
You say, "Oh, look! There is a way through the back here!
Let me try it around the back! Maybe, this will take me to my destiny!
Maybe, this will take me to the throne! Oh my God!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Do you know what has happened?
I finally reached a dead end!
No way here, no way there!
Only way back.
I have gone all this way, wasted so much time
wasted so many opportunities, thinking I'm taking a shortcut
thinking it would take me to my destiny
and each suggestion of satan has only taken me away.
And look, I can see it! I can see the destiny there!
I can see it but I can't get there.
Oh, it's very painful.
It's very painful, people of God.
It's very painful.
Let me tell you something.
Only Jesus, the Owner of your destiny can take you to your destiny.
Political connections cannot.
Worldly associations cannot.
Powerful affiliations cannot.
Only Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And now, here I am.
I have to now go back; I have got to retrace my steps.
I wasted so much time.
I have got my hands dirty.
I have got my heart corrupted, thinking I'm going to my destiny,
thinking I'm getting to the throne; not knowing, I'm only destroying myself.
Oh God!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So here we are, retracing our steps.
Many old people today are doing what they were supposed to have done when they were younger
but tried to move the hands of the clock forward;
they tried to beat God's time and found themselves back to where they began,
back to where they started, back to square one.
Here I am again.
Here I am again with the same obstacle.
Now, let me tell you something, people of God.
If I had waited patiently for the Lord,
if I had not listened to that deceptive, destructive voice,
let me tell you what would have happened.
Sorry, sir. Just come here.
For this example, my brother here will represent me and you,
and I'm going to represent God when you are in such kind of situation.
So my brother, just stand here.
My brother has tried everything to remove the obstacle -
tried power, might, human effort - no way!
And he is waiting on God, waiting for God's time.
God, the moment he sees this His son has enough experience and maturity,
he has been prepared well enough,
he has those tools of patience, perseverance and endurance,
his desire for Christ has been strengthened -
do you know what God will do? - "Come, sir, follow me!"
"Come!"
"Take your destiny!"
"Take it!"
You take it!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, what happened there?
At God's appointed time, you will move without any personal effort required,
without any stress, tension, pressure.
You just move because God has already prepared the way.
Now, what am I trying to say here, brethren?
No matter your situation as a Christian, God is always one step ahead of you.
He's there. He's with you in the trial; He's with you in the trouble.
He may not seem to respond immediately because He's testing your patience.
He wants to make sure that by the time you reach your destiny,
you will not crack, explode and lose everything because you don't have enough preparation.
Look at the three Hebrew men that were thrown into the fiery furnace.
Nebuchadnezzar and his servants looked in, and they saw four men.
And the fourth looked like the Son of God.
Because before they were thrown into the furnace, Jesus was already one step ahead of them.
I don't know what furnace you have been thrown in today.
I don't know what you are facing.
Perhaps you are in the furnace of false accusation, the furnace of persecution,
the furnace of disappointment or sickness.
One thing I know, people of God, as Christians, God is one step ahead of you.
Don't give up; don't give in.
Allow Him to stay burning within you so you can endure whatever condition you face
and your challenges will make you stronger.
Jesus Christ is the best example of this incredible principle.
You know the life of our Lord Jesus Christ.
Jesus lived on the earth 33 years.
The first 30 years were preparation.
Even though He knew He had come to change, save, deliver the world,
He waited patiently for the fullness of time.
Just imagine how many people went into his carpenter shop
who were sick, oppressed, demon-possessed
and He had the power to set them free, deliver them but it was not yet time.
Even when He started His ministry, His mother, His brothers were urging Him,
"Go ahead, go on, show yourself to the world!"
Jesus said, "My time has not yet come. For you, anytime can be right".
In three years, Jesus Christ turned the entire world upside down.
But look today, even this impatience has infiltrated Kingdom business.
You see people today, they don't want to march with God; they just want to march for Him.
Marching with God is a time of discipleship.
Marching for God is a time of acting on His behalf.
People today, they go into ministry, they just want to go straight to start praying, ministering to people.
So many people have seen it - pastors, ministers of God from around the world come to this church.
They will say to the man of God, "T.B. Joshua, please pray for me for power.
Pray for me for anointing" but I have not heard anyone say, "Pray for me for character".
Character takes time and preparation but character is the food of anointing.
Look, let me give you an example of this.
I was watching a Christian programme the other day and it came up an advert.
They said, "Come to this prophetic school and learn how to prophesy in three days".
Three days? My God.
Look, I'm not trying to tell you that there is nothing impossible with God.
God is God; there is nothing He cannot do.
But spiritual gifts are not subject to human timing.
When Jesus spoke to His disciples in Acts 1, He said,
"Wait in Jerusalem until the promise of the Father".
They now began to query Him about the time He would come.
He told them in Acts 1:7, "It is not for you to know the times or dates
the Father has set by His own authority".
We just wait for God; we don't push Him or instruct Him in the way He should go.
We submit to His will and at God's time everything is beautiful.
Look, I realise - and once again I'm calling this message as a time of self-examination -
I realise that the majority of people, especially the young people today,
the reason that they are so much in a hurry, so impatient
is because they are comparing themselves with others.
So I want to give you a powerful secret that I believe will help you today.
There is no competition in destiny.
What is yours is yours.
You hear some people today say, "This guy took my star.
He took my destiny, he took this".
There is only one person who can stop you from reaching your destiny - you.
Why then are we busy envying; why then are we so jealous -
envying ourselves, jealous of ourselves?
Envying is a waste of time.
Look, let me try and practicalise this.
Sorry, sir, if the two of you can just stand up.
Now, my brothers you see here are colleagues and they are both doing business.
Today, you will see that maybe one of them, the business starts moving;
the business starts running.
The other one, the business is a bit slow, a little bit stagnant.
He will begin to look and say, "What is this guy doing that his business is running?"
After all, I started the business before him; I'm more equipped.
I have more experience. What is going on?
Maybe he has gone somewhere; maybe there is a charm.
Maybe it is this, maybe it is that".
You begin to look for faults; you begin to diagnose this, that.
Envy, jealousy, comparing yourself with others.
But let me tell you something, people of God.
My brother's time to walk may be my brother's time to run.
And this my brother's time to run may be his time to walk.
Why then are we jealous of ourselves?
Why do we compare ourselves?
Our journey is different.
What matters is that you follow the ways of the Lord.
Not that we are fighting ourselves, envy - "This guy is young and he has gone up like that."
You don't know his journey; his journey is different to yours.
His destiny is different to yours.
You may have your seats, sirs.
As I round up, let me challenge you.
What you are praying for today, are you prepared for it?
Many of us are praying, "God, bless my business, bless this, I want this, that".
Are you ready for it?
Prophet T.B. Joshua said that many of us want to become managing directors of companies
but we cannot even manage our own homes.
Many of us want to be the owners of our own companies
but we cannot keep our own car clean.
Many young people are here today; it is not just God that brought them here.
They are looking for a young lady, young man -
"God, send me my destined partner, my husband, my wife" because of your age.
You see others getting married; your parents say, "You must marry";
the society says, "You must marry"; you want to get married at all costs.
But even your own bedroom, you can't keep it clean.
Let me give a word of advice to young people around the world.
And this is a message from Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Because satan is attacking the institution of the Christian home today.
Marriages around the world seem to be scattering; divorce is rampant.
There are two things that build a successful marriage:
the right time and the right person.
Please take note: It is not the right person that brings the right time.
It is the right time that brings the right person.
Wait for God's time and your marriage will stand the test of time.
Don't marry because by society, everyone is getting married.
"My age - I'm supposed to get married."
No, wait for God's time so that by the time you are equipped, you are prepared,
you are at the place of your destiny.
At that time, by the time you get married, you can manage your home,
not just populate the world with children that will end up becoming a nuisance to society
but bring children that will build, invest and change the world.
In conclusion:
God does not want any one of us to come to the end of our days, saying,
"I could have been, I should have been, I would have been".
It would be very painful if you realise this by the time your hair has greyed,
your strength has waned and your dreams have been scattered.
Wait patiently for the Lord.
God's time is the best.
I'm not saying you should be idle.
I'm not saying you should just sit down and let God's time come. No!
Work as if everything depends on you; pray as if everything depends on God.
Combine hard work with quiet confidence in God for the future.
Make use of every opportunity that comes your way and see every minute as important.
One thing you must know:
Only by trusting in Christ can your life have value.
Only by trusting in Christ can your life have meaning.
You will be able to say with the Psalmist, "What else do I want in Heaven but God?
Since I have God, what else do I want on earth?
My mind, my body may grow weak but God is my strength; He is all I need".
Brethren, there is no reason to rush
for I want to assure you, we shall reach the end of this road
in God's time, in God's way, for God's glory.
May God bless His Word in the midst of our hearts, in Jesus' name.
TT: Mel Flowers 06/01/2019
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 13/01/2019